
Describe the events or circumstances which cause this action to commence.
*Who is the primary actor performing this action?
*What other primary or secondary actors are involved?
*How is the actor notified to start the action?
*When must the action commence?
*What are the constraints for scheduling and completing the action?
*What dependencies exist between this action and other actions?
*What conditions or constraints must be satisfied prior to commencing this action?

What actions are performed by the actor?
*What are the step-by-step procedures or tasks performed by the actor?
*What regulations, policies, or procedures are followed or referenced?
*What calculations, schedules, computations, or algorithms are involved in completing the action.
*What other actors are involved?
*What computer systems (besides the target system) are involved?
*What decisions are made by the actor?
*What exceptional processing or error processing occurs?

What information does the actor contribute?
*What knowledge or skill does the actor posses that’s required to complete this action?
*What does the actor need to know before completing this action?
*How is the actor dependent on other actors to complete this operation?
*What does the actor know about other actors or non-actors?

What information does the actor expect to receive?
*What information does the actor receive from the computer system?
*What information does the actor receive from other actors?

What are the results of this operation?
*What happens as a result of this operation?
*How does data change internally or externally to the system?
*What physical changes occur?
*What previous values should be retained for historical reference?
What algorithms or processing considerations are involved?
*What calculations are involved in the action?
*What special processing (e.g. sorting, matching, schedules) is involved in the action?
*How is data transformed or changed?
*What data formats are used?
*What are the sources for algorithms or schedules (e.g. regulating agencies, professional organizations)?

Should this action be recorded as an event?
*Is this action time sensitive, or does it relate to other time sensitive actions?
*Does this action “start the clock?”
*Would the recording of this action assist in unrelated actions?
*Do performance constraints apply which should be measured for conformance?

